<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30124455</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>10</Month>            <Day>04</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Print">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-7401</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">                    <Volume>26</Volume>                    <Issue>4</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Technology and health care : official journal of the European Society for Engineering and Medicine</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Technol Health Care</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>Early diagnosis and detection of breast cancer.</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>729-759</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3233/THC-181277</ELocationID>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Breast cancer is the most common malignancy in women. It is often characterized by a lack of early symptoms, which results in late detection of the disease. Detection at advanced stages of the decease implies the treatment is more difficult and uncertain. The appropriate screening programs have been conducted within the organized preventive examinations and have made significant contributions to the early breast cancer detection.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">It is necessary to improve the screening process in order to reduce the percentage of female population that is not covered by screening programs and increase the number of early-detected breast cancers. The improvement of the screening program may be reflected in the following: more efficient determination of the list of the women who have to undergo preventive examination, introduction of screening program in thermography as a diagnostic method applied in pre-screening stage, more efficient analysis of mammograms and continuous follow up of patients.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The identification of target population for breast cancer screening program has been based on the age of women. The improvement of the early breast cancer diagnosis process proposed in this paper is reflected in more efficient determination of the group of women who have to undergo preventive examination based on the factors affecting the occurrence of breast cancer. Inclusion of the pre-screening phase in which thermal imaging could be applied and software support to mammographic detection of tumor are suggested.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This paper describes the breast cancer, current screening program and techniques for early-stage breast cancer detection, module of medical information system MEDIS.NET for creating screening list based on the analysis of risk factors affecting the occurrence of breast cancer, mammography and role of thermal imaging in the process of early breast cancer detection. It also presents an overview on important achievements in computer-aided detection and diagnosis of breast cancer in mammography and thermography.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Based on the obtained results, dynamics of preventive examinations for particular groups of women that is different from the standard two-year examinations, can be successfully defined. It can be concluded that the use of a computer system for tumor diagnosis in mammogram based on various methods of image processing can help doctors in decision-making, while the use of thermal imaging in the pre-screening phase would significantly reduce the list of women for screening mammograms.</AbstractText>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Milosevic</LastName>                    <ForeName>Marina</ForeName>                    <Initials>M</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, Faculty of Technical Sciences, University of Kragujevac, Cacak 32000, Serbia.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Jankovic</LastName>                    <ForeName>Dragan</ForeName>                    <Initials>D</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Electronic Engineering, University of Nis, Nis 18000, Serbia.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Milenkovic</LastName>                    <ForeName>Aleksandar</ForeName>                    <Initials>A</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Electronic Engineering, University of Nis, Nis 18000, Serbia.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Stojanov</LastName>                    <ForeName>Dragan</ForeName>                    <Initials>D</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Nis, Nis 18108, Serbia.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>eng</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Netherlands</Country>            <MedlineTA>Technol Health Care</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>9314590</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>0928-7329</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mammography</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factors</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">screening program</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thermography</Keyword>        </KeywordList>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>8</Month>                <Day>21</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>8</Month>                <Day>21</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>8</Month>                <Day>21</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30124455</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="pii">THC181277</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/THC-181277</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>