<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Data-Review" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30038434</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>08</Month>            <Day>29</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0465-5893</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">                    <Volume>69</Volume>                    <Issue>4</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                        <Month>Aug</Month>                        <Day>20</Day>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Medycyna pracy</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Med Pr</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>[The prophylactic operational model integrated with occupational healthcare - Prophylactic of some types of cancers among women].</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>439-455</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">80912</ELocationID>            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.13075/mp.5893.00665</ELocationID>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText>Periodical medical examinations are mandatory for employees in Poland. This rule makes a unique opportunity during occupational health services for implementation of prophylactic activities focused on early diagnosis of various diseases, including cancers. Epidemiological data about cancers is alarming and what is more, further increase in development of cancers is being predicted in population overall. The highest incidence of cancers in the case of Polish women belongs to breast cancer (21.7% of diagnosed cancers in general), while the morbidity rate for uterine cancer, ovarian cancer and cervical cancer amounts to 7.4%, 4.7% and 3.5%, respectively. The aim of this study was to elaborate an algorithm of prophylactic activities integrated with the occupational healthcare system, based on medical literature review and guidelines concerning prophylaxis of selected cancers. Polish cancers' prophylaxis programs related to risk factors were presented in this publication and practical indications for occupational healthcare physicians were worked out. Med Pr 2018;69(4):439-455.</AbstractText>                <CopyrightInformation>This work is available in Open Access model and licensed under a CC BY-NC 3.0 PL license.</CopyrightInformation>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Wiszniewska</LastName>                    <ForeName>Marta</ForeName>                    <Initials>M</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Instytut Medycyny Pracy im. prof. J. Nofera / Nofer Institute of Occupational Medicine, Łódź, Poland (Klinika Chorób Zawodowych i Zdrowia Środowiskowego / Department of Occupational Diseases and Environmental Health). marta.wiszniewska@imp.lodz.pl.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Magnuska</LastName>                    <ForeName>Jadwiga</ForeName>                    <Initials>J</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Instytut Medycyny Pracy im. prof. J. Nofera / Nofer Institute of Occupational Medicine, Łódź, Poland (Klinika Chorób Zawodowych i Zdrowia Środowiskowego / Department of Occupational Diseases and Environmental Health). jadziama@imp.lodz.pl.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Lipińska-Ojrzanowska</LastName>                    <ForeName>Agnieszka</ForeName>                    <Initials>A</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Instytut Medycyny Pracy im. prof. J. Nofera / Nofer Institute of Occupational Medicine, Łódź, Poland (Klinika Chorób Zawodowych i Zdrowia Środowiskowego / Department of Occupational Diseases and Environmental Health). lipinska@imp.lodz.pl.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Pepłońska</LastName>                    <ForeName>Beata</ForeName>                    <Initials>B</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Instytut Medycyny Pracy im. prof. J. Nofera / Nofer Institute of Occupational Medicine, Łódź, Poland (Zakład Epidemiologii Środowiskowej / Department of Environmental Epidemiology). Beata.Peplonska@imp.lodz.pl.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Hanke</LastName>                    <ForeName>Wojciech</ForeName>                    <Initials>W</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Instytut Medycyny Pracy im. prof. J. Nofera / Nofer Institute of Occupational Medicine, Łódź, Poland (Zakład Epidemiologii Środowiskowej / Department of Environmental Epidemiology). Wojciech.Hanke@imp.lodz.pl.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Kalinka</LastName>                    <ForeName>Jarosław</ForeName>                    <Initials>J</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Uniwersytet Medyczny w Łodzi / Medical University of Lodz, Łódź, Poland (Klinika Perinatologii, I Katedry Ginekologii i Położnictwa / Department of Perinatology, 1st Chair of Obstetrics and Gynecology). j.kalinka@csk.am.lodz.pl.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Skręt-Magierło</LastName>                    <ForeName>Joanna</ForeName>                    <Initials>J</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Uniwersytet Rzeszowski/ University of Rzeszow, Rzeszów, Poland (Kliniczny Szpital Wojewódzki nr 1 im. Fryderyka Chopina w Rzeszowie, Klinika Ginekologii i Położnictwa / Frederick Chopin Clinical Provincial Hospital No. 1 Rzeszow, Obstetrics and Gynecology Clinic). joannaskret@wp.pl.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Zadrożny</LastName>                    <ForeName>Marek</ForeName>                    <Initials>M</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Instytut Centrum Zdrowia Matki Polki / Institute of Polish Mother's Memorial Hospital, Łódź, Poland (Klinika Chirurgii Onkologicznej i Chorób Piersi / Department of Oncological Surgery and Breast Diseases). zadrozny.lodz@wp.pl.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Walusiak-Skorupa</LastName>                    <ForeName>Jolanta</ForeName>                    <Initials>J</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Instytut Medycyny Pracy im. prof. J. Nofera / Nofer Institute of Occupational Medicine, Łódź, Poland (Klinika Chorób Zawodowych i Zdrowia Środowiskowego / Department of Occupational Diseases and Environmental Health). jolantaw@imp.lodz.pl.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>pol</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>            <VernacularTitle>Model działań profilaktycznych zintegrowany z opieką profilaktyczną nad pracownikami – zapobieganie niektórym typom nowotworów wśród kobiet.</VernacularTitle>            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>07</Month>                <Day>23</Day>            </ArticleDate>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Poland</Country>            <MedlineTA>Med Pr</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>0376642</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>0465-5893</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="pol">            <AbstractText>W Polsce pracownicy podlegają obowiązkowym okresowym badaniom lekarskim. Stwarza to unikalną szansę wdrożenia działań nakierowanych na wczesne wykrywanie wielu schorzeń, w tym chorób nowotworowych, w system opieki profilaktycznej nad pracującymi. Dane epidemiologiczne dotyczące chorób nowotworowych są niepokojące – co więcej, prognozuje się dalszy wzrost zachorowań na nowotwory złośliwe w populacji generalnej. Najczęstszym nowotworem wśród polskich kobiet jest rak piersi odpowiadający za 21,7% zachorowań, podczas gdy nowotwory złośliwe trzonu macicy, jajnika i szyjki macicy stanowią, odpowiednio, 7,4%, 4,7% i 3,5% zachorowań. Celem niniejszej pracy było opracowanie algorytmu działań profilaktycznych zintegrowanych z opieką profilaktyczną nad pracownikami, bazującego na przeglądzie piśmiennictwa medycznego oraz obowiązujących wytycznych dotyczących zapobieganiu wybranym typom nowotworów. W publikacji przedstawiono funkcjonujące programy profilaktyczne chorób nowotworowych i ich czynniki ryzyka. Opracowano także praktyczne rozwiązania pozwalające na włączenie profesjonalistów zajmujących się ochroną zdrowia pracowników w profilaktykę niektórych typów nowotworów występujących u kobiet. Med. Pr. 2018;69(4):439–455.</AbstractText>        </OtherAbstract>        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cervical cancer</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast cancer</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancers</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occupational healthcare service</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ovarian cancer</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prophylaxis</Keyword>        </KeywordList>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>7</Month>                <Day>25</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>7</Month>                <Day>25</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>7</Month>                <Day>25</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30038434</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="pii">80912</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13075/mp.5893.00665</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>