<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Data-Review" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30121682</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>08</Month>            <Day>19</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Print">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0300-5283</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">                    <Volume>73</Volume>                    <Issue>4</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                        <Month>Aug</Month>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>The Medical journal of Malaysia</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Med. J. Malaysia</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>The uptake of Mammogram screening in Malaysia and its associated factors: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>202-211</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This review aimed to summarise the trend of mammogram screening uptake published in local studies between years 2006 and 2015 among the Malaysian women aged 40 years and above, and identify the associated factors and barriers, as well as discuss limitations of the studies and research gaps.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic review was conducted on breast cancer screening studies among Malaysian women, published between January 2006 and December 2015. Online databases were searched using keywords: &quot;mammogram&quot;, &quot;mammography&quot;, &quot;uptake&quot;, &quot;breast cancer screening&quot; and &quot;Malaysia&quot;.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Thirteen original articles were reviewed. The rate of mammography uptake ranged between 3.6% and 30.9% among the general population, and 80.3% among personnel of a tertiary hospital. Factors associated with mammogram screening were clinical breast examination, age, income, knowledge on breast cancer and mammogram, perceived susceptibility to breast cancer, ethnicity and education level. Barriers to mammogram screening were lack of knowledge, embarrassment, fear of cancer diagnosis, perception that breast screening was unnecessary, lack of coping skills and pain during procedure. However, almost all of the studies could not be generalised beyond the study sample because of the limited number of sites and respondents; and most data were self-reported with no objective measures of the responses.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Mammogram screening uptake among women in selected communities were generally low. Further studies involving the general population are essential. Future studies should also explore the availability, affordability and accessibility of this service especially in the pursuit of achieving universal health coverage in breast cancer management.</AbstractText>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Aidalina</LastName>                    <ForeName>M</ForeName>                    <Initials>M</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Center, International Center for Casemix and Clinical Coding, Malaysia. aidalina75@gmail.com.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Syed Mohamed</LastName>                    <ForeName>A S J</ForeName>                    <Initials>ASJ</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Center, International Center for Casemix and Clinical Coding, Malaysia.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>eng</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Malaysia</Country>            <MedlineTA>Med J Malaysia</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>0361547</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>0300-5283</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>8</Month>                <Day>20</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>8</Month>                <Day>20</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>8</Month>                <Day>20</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30121682</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>