<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedBookArticle>    <BookDocument>        <PMID Version="1">25719192</PMID>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK274564</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>        <Book>            <Publisher>                <PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName>                <PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation>            </Publisher>            <BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle>            <PubDate>                <Year>1993</Year>            </PubDate>            <BeginningDate>                <Year>1993</Year>            </BeginningDate>            <EndingDate>                <Year>2018</Year>            </EndingDate>            <AuthorList Type="editors">                <Author>                    <LastName>Adam</LastName>                    <ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName>                    <Initials>MP</Initials>                </Author>                <Author>                    <LastName>Ardinger</LastName>                    <ForeName>Holly H</ForeName>                    <Initials>HH</Initials>                </Author>                <Author>                    <LastName>Pagon</LastName>                    <ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName>                    <Initials>RA</Initials>                </Author>                <Author>                    <LastName>Wallace</LastName>                    <ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName>                    <Initials>SE</Initials>                </Author>                <Author>                    <LastName>Bean</LastName>                    <ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName>                    <Initials>LJH</Initials>                </Author>                <Author>                    <LastName>Stephens</LastName>                    <ForeName>Karen</ForeName>                    <Initials>K</Initials>                </Author>                <Author>                    <LastName>Amemiya</LastName>                    <ForeName>Anne</ForeName>                    <Initials>A</Initials>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Medium>Internet</Medium>        </Book>        <ArticleTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright">Fibrous Dysplasia/McCune-Albright Syndrome</ArticleTitle>        <Language>eng</Language>        <AuthorList Type="authors">            <Author>                <LastName>Boyce</LastName>                <ForeName>Alison M</ForeName>                <Initials>AM</Initials>                <AffiliationInfo>                    <Affiliation>Skeletal Disorders and Mineral Homeostasis Section, Craniofacial and Skeletal Diseases Branch, National Institute of Dental and Craniofacial Research, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland</Affiliation>                </AffiliationInfo>                <AffiliationInfo>                    <Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology and Diabetes, Children’s National Health System, Bone Health Program, Division of Orthopaedics and Sports Medicine, Children’s National Health System, Washington, DC</Affiliation>                </AffiliationInfo>            </Author>            <Author>                <LastName>Florenzano</LastName>                <ForeName>Pablo</ForeName>                <Initials>P</Initials>                <AffiliationInfo>                    <Affiliation>Skeletal Disorders and Mineral Homeostasis Section, National Institute of Dental and Craniofacial Research, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland</Affiliation>                </AffiliationInfo>                <AffiliationInfo>                    <Affiliation>Endocrinology Department, Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile, Santiago, Chile</Affiliation>                </AffiliationInfo>            </Author>            <Author>                <LastName>de Castro</LastName>                <ForeName>Luis F</ForeName>                <Initials>LF</Initials>                <AffiliationInfo>                    <Affiliation>Skeletal Disorders and Mineral Homeostasis Section, National Institute of Dental and Craniofacial Research, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland</Affiliation>                </AffiliationInfo>            </Author>            <Author>                <LastName>Collins</LastName>                <ForeName>Michael T</ForeName>                <Initials>MT</Initials>                <AffiliationInfo>                    <Affiliation>Chief, Skeletal Disorders and Mineral Homeostasis Section, Craniofacial and Skeletal Diseases Branch, National Institute of Dental and Craniofacial Research, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland</Affiliation>                </AffiliationInfo>            </Author>        </AuthorList>        <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>        <Abstract>            <AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS">Fibrous dysplasia/McCune-Albright syndrome (FD/MAS), the result of an early embryonic postzygotic somatic activating pathogenic variant in <i>GNAS</i> (encoding the cAMP pathway-associated G-protein, G<sub>s</sub>α), is characterized by involvement of the skin, skeleton, and certain endocrine organs. However, because G<sub>s</sub>α signaling is ubiquitous, additional tissues may be affected. Café au lait skin macules are common and are usually the first manifestation of the disease, apparent at or shortly after birth. Fibrous dysplasia (FD), which can involve any part and combination of the craniofacial, axial, and/or appendicular skeleton, can range from an isolated, asymptomatic monostotic lesion discovered incidentally to severe disabling polyostotic disease involving practically the entire skeleton and leading to progressive scoliosis, facial deformity, and loss of mobility, vision, and/or hearing. Endocrinopathies include: Gonadotropin-independent precocious puberty resulting from recurrent ovarian cysts in girls and autonomous testosterone production in boys; Testicular lesions with or without associated gonadotropin-independent precocious puberty; Thyroid lesions with or without non-autoimmune hyperthyroidism; Growth hormone excess; FGF23-mediated phosphate wasting with or without hypophosphatemia in association with fibrous dysplasia; and Neonatal hypercortisolism. The prognosis for individuals with FD/MAS is based on disease location and severity.</AbstractText>            <AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">In most individuals, the diagnosis of FD/MAS is based on the finding of two or more typical clinical features. In individuals whose only clinical finding is monostotic fibrous dysplasia, identification of a somatic activating pathogenic variant in <i>GNAS</i> by molecular genetic testing is required to establish the diagnosis. Variant detection depends on the level of mosaicism in the tissue and the sensitivity of the technique.</AbstractText>            <AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations:</i> Management is most effectively accomplished by a multidisciplinary team of specialists. FD. Management focuses on optimizing function and minimizing morbidity related to fractures and deformity (including scoliosis). Precocious puberty. Treatment prevents bone age advancement and compromise of adult height. For girls, the aromatase inhibitor letrozole is used; for boys, treatment options are less well established. Thyroid disease. Methimazole effectively manages hyperthyroidism; however, because hyperthyroidism is persistent, thyroidectomy is common. Growth hormone excess. Medical therapy is the preferred first-line treatment; options include (alone or in combination) octreotide and the growth hormone receptor antagonist pegvisomant. Hypercortisolism. Treatment varies by the presentation of neonatal Cushing syndrome. <i>Surveillance:</i> FD/MAS. Monitor for the following: Infants: clinical signs of hypercortisolism. All children: growth acceleration and other clinical signs of precocious puberty and/or growth hormone excess. Children: Age &lt;5 years: thyroid function abnormalities. With thyroid abnormalities on ultrasound examination but normal thyroid function: periodic monitoring of thyroid function. Males: testicular lesions (physical examination and testicular ultrasound). Individuals on: Pegvisomant: hepatotoxicity. Somatostatin analogs: signs and symptoms of gallbladder disease. Females: breast cancer (earlier than is recommended for the general population). FD: Periodic radiographs to monitor existing FD and development of new lesions. Periodic serum phosphorus (for development of hypophosphatemia) and 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels. Craniofacial FD: yearly vision and hearing evaluations; periodic skull CT; routine serum IGF-1 levels through young adulthood. Spine FD: close monitoring for progressive scoliosis. <i>Agents/circumstances to avoid:</i> Contact sports and other high-risk activities (when skeletal involvement is significant); prophylactic optic nerve decompression (in individuals with craniofacial FD); surgical removal of ovarian cysts; radiation therapy for treatment of FD; risk factors for malignancy (e.g., radiation exposure).</AbstractText>            <AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING">FD/MAS is not inherited. No parent of a child with FD/MAS has been demonstrated to have any significant, distinctive manifestations of the disorder. The risk to sibs is expected to be the same as in the general population. There are no verified instances of vertical transmission of FD/MAS.</AbstractText>            <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2018, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>        </Abstract>        <Sections>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle>            </Section>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle>            </Section>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.Clinical_Characteristics">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle>            </Section>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.Genetically_Related_Alle">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle>            </Section>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle>            </Section>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.Management">Management</SectionTitle>            </Section>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle>            </Section>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle>            </Section>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle>            </Section>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.References">References</SectionTitle>            </Section>            <Section>                <SectionTitle book="gene" part="mccune-albright" sec="mccune-albright.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle>            </Section>        </Sections>        <ContributionDate>            <Year>2015</Year>            <Month>2</Month>            <Day>26</Day>        </ContributionDate>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>8</Month>            <Day>16</Day>        </DateRevised>        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">            <Grant>                <GrantID>HHSN276201400262U</GrantID>                <Acronym>LM</Acronym>                <Agency>NLM NIH HHS</Agency>                <Country>United States</Country>            </Grant>        </GrantList>        <ItemList ListType="Synonyms">            <Item>FD/MAS</Item>        </ItemList>    </BookDocument>    <PubmedBookData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>8</Month>                <Day>16</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>8</Month>                <Day>16</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2015</Year>                <Month>2</Month>                <Day>27</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25719192</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>