<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30056726</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>07</Month>            <Day>30</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Print">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2304-3873</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">                    <Volume>7</Volume>                    <Issue>3</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                        <Month>Jun</Month>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Chinese clinical oncology</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Chin Clin Oncol</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>Resection of primary lesion for patients with metastatic breast cancer: where are we now?</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>24</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.21037/cco.2018.05.03</ELocationID>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText>It is largely unclear that whether or not surgical resection of the primary tumors could confer survival benefit among patients with metastatic breast cancer at initial presentation. We thoroughly reviewed the up-to-date evidence on surgical resection of the primary lesion in metastatic breast cancer, including comparative studies (of particular interest in risk modifiers, the type, and timing of surgical procedures), Chinese and international guidelines, as well as the progress of clinical trials. Partial modified radical mastectomy and breast-conserving surgery are by far the most common choices for patients with metastatic breast cancer. Patients with certain characteristics, for example, younger than 45 years of age or with oligo-metastasis, might benefit from the surgery. The type and timing of surgical procedures are still in debate according to the guidelines from different countries. Forthcoming evidence from the ongoing clinical trials might help close the knowledge gaps in surgical treatment for patients with metastatic breast cancer and aid the decision-making in clinical practice.</AbstractText>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Hu</LastName>                    <ForeName>Qiancheng</ForeName>                    <Initials>Q</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Cancer Center, West China Hospital, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Zhong</LastName>                    <ForeName>Xiaorong</ForeName>                    <Initials>X</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Cancer Center, West China Hospital, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; State Key Laboratory of Biotherapy, Laboratory of Tumor Molecular Diagnosis, West China Hospital, National Collaborative Innovation Center for Biotherapy, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; Clinical Research Center for Breast, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Liu</LastName>                    <ForeName>Xu</ForeName>                    <Initials>X</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Biotherapy, Laboratory of Tumor Molecular Diagnosis, West China Hospital, National Collaborative Innovation Center for Biotherapy, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Xie</LastName>                    <ForeName>Yuxin</ForeName>                    <Initials>Y</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Cancer Center, West China Hospital, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; State Key Laboratory of Biotherapy, Laboratory of Tumor Molecular Diagnosis, West China Hospital, National Collaborative Innovation Center for Biotherapy, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Hu</LastName>                    <ForeName>Kejia</ForeName>                    <Initials>K</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Biotherapy, Laboratory of Tumor Molecular Diagnosis, West China Hospital, National Collaborative Innovation Center for Biotherapy, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>He</LastName>                    <ForeName>Ping</ForeName>                    <Initials>P</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Cancer Center, West China Hospital, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; Clinical Research Center for Breast, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Lu</LastName>                    <ForeName>Donghao</ForeName>                    <Initials>D</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Cancer Center, West China Hospital, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; Clinical Research Center for Breast, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Zheng</LastName>                    <ForeName>Hong</ForeName>                    <Initials>H</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Cancer Center, West China Hospital, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; State Key Laboratory of Biotherapy, Laboratory of Tumor Molecular Diagnosis, West China Hospital, National Collaborative Innovation Center for Biotherapy, West China Medical School, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China; Clinical Research Center for Breast, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610041, China. hzheng@scu.edu.cn.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>eng</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>China</Country>            <MedlineTA>Chin Clin Oncol</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>101608375</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>2304-3865</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">distant metastasis</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resection of the primary lesion</Keyword>        </KeywordList>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>03</Month>                <Day>10</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>05</Month>                <Day>03</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>7</Month>                <Day>31</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>7</Month>                <Day>31</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>7</Month>                <Day>31</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30056726</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/cco.2018.05.03</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>